Niray Hathi

📞 +91-7574944533 🛛 🔀 imniravhathi@gmail.com 👂 Gandhinagar, Gujarat 382421

SUMMARY

I have been working professionally as iOS + iOT Developer for over 7 years. Through those years I have become advanced in developing full feature apps with Objective-C, Swift, SwiftUi languages and IoT technology as well with WIFI, BLE, core Bluetooth, Zigbee, MQTT etc. Although I can easily develop all aspects of an iOS app from the networking layer to the front end.

SKILLS

Swift

iOS SDK

Swift Ui

• Git

Objective - C

Azure(TFS)

Flutter

EXPERIENCE

Assistant Consultant

03/2022 - Current

Tata Consultancy Services

- Contribute to the architecture, design and implementation of consumer-facing features in the UPS App
- · Build compelling in-app experiences that will reach users globally
- Collaborate with the product and design team(s) influence the roadmap and product development of UPS's App and services
- · Create and maintain internal shared frameworks and libraries
- Shape the future of optimized analytics at UPS from the ground up with innovative data tools for analytics
- Evolve UPS's architecture to support multiple authentication flows, account management, and integrations
- · Mentor, collaborate, and learn from innovative and passionate team members

Module Lead 09/2020 - 03/2022

Wipro Pune

- Worked as Specialist Consultant for HSBC on MobileX app in Customer Support journey.
- Remained knowledgeable in latest guidelines and best practices to ensure delivery of regulatory compliant service.

Senior Software Engineer

04/2019 - 09/2020

VOLANSYS, ACL Digital Ahmedabad

- Design and build advanced applications for the iOS + IoT platform.
- Explored the IoT technology with WI-FI, BLE, core Bluetooth, Zigbee, Bluetooth, Wi-Fi, MQTT etc.
- · Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new features
- Work on bug fixing and improving application performance
- Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency.

Software Developer

09/2018 - 04/2019

Mobiuso

Design, develop, and maintain native iOS applications using Swift and Objective-C

- Develop user interfaces and create custom views using UIKit, Core Animation, and other frameworks
- Develop custom frameworks and libraries to be used in iOS applications
- Integrate third-party libraries and APIs into existing applications Develop automated tests to ensure the quality of the code

Senior Software Engineer

10/2015 - 08/2018

DRC Systems Gandhinagar

- Worked closely with our product and design teams to customize apps for iOS platform
- Implemented custom native user interfaces using the latest iOS programming techniques Built reusable iOS software components for interface
- Analyzed and optimized UI and back-end application code for efficiency and performance Lead development team in architecture and coding patterns and best practices
- Updated project to latest version of swift/Objective C language
- Key decision maker in application architecture guidance and project planning and execution
- Shared knowledge with mobile development team with regard to the company's vision, opportunities and challenges
- Collaborated with other development leads(Android/ Platform/API) on architectural vision and roadmap
- · Agile development methodology based on multiple sprints and continuous delivery

Iphone Developer

12/2014 - 09/2015

Hyperlink Infosystem

- Working with iOS SDK and Objective C
- Started working with Swift, the latest apple programming language released last month Experience working with remote data via REST and JSON
- · Experience with third-party libraries and APIs
- Working knowledge of the general mobile landscape, architectures, trends and emerging technologies
- · Solid understanding of the full mobile development cycle

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Master of Computer Applications (M.C.A.)

01/2015

Gujarat Technological University, Ahmedbabd

Bachelor of Computer Application (B.C.A)

01/2012

Saurashtra University

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth: 08/07/92

CUSTOM

- English
- Hindi
- Gujarati

CERTIFICATIONS

- · iOS White Belt Assessment.
- Codility Sliver Award for the Nickel Challenge.
- · Dart Programming Language.